Redwood Canyon Ramblers collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 2: Event recordings and related materials
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at The Cabale, August 16, 1963, AFC 2011/011: SR05
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR05; RXJ 0534; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:32:19, Side B: 00:28:54): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Probably the original tape. Recorded at The Cabale, 2504 San Pablo, Berkeley, California. Personnel: Scott Hambly, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith, Sandy Rothman). Continued on SR06.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 281.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1963-08-16t01.aif - rcr1963-08-16t22.aif; 22 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tuning/"Little Birdie" 00:02:46
      "Georgia Rose" 00:03:24
      "Wildwood Flower" 00:01:58
      "Molly And Tenbrooks" 00:03:18
      "I Ain't Broke But I'm Badly Bent" ("next song dedicated to Roosevelt Watson") 00:02:17
      "Pike County Breakdown" (hey Neil, they say you had a rough time sleeping last night") 00:03:20
      "Love Please Come Home" 00:02:48
      "After Dark" 00:02:34
      "Cripple Creek" 00:01:44
      Intro/"Midnight Train" 00:03:26
      Band intros 00:01:14
      "Homestead On The Farm" [partial; reel direction change] 00:03:20
      "New Camptown Races" 00:02:21
      "I'll Walk Out On You" 00:03:00
      "Childish Love" ("I believe there are a few Rick Shubb's in the audience") 00:03:14
      "Rawhide" 00:02:54
      "Lost Highway" ("by George, I think I'm gonna go out and have a smoke") 00:04:43
      "We'll Meet Again Sweetheart" 00:02:45
      Joke about duck hunting 00:01:23
      "Wheel Hoss" 00:02:10
      "I Am A Pilgrim" 00:03:51
      "Cumberland Gap" 00:01:38
    - Song list and production notes for SR05 and SR06, January 5, 2011, 1963 August 16 (Reel 281&282).txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list, undated, 1963 August 16 Set 1_2 (Reel#281).pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at The Cabale, August 16, 1963, AFC 2011/011: SR06
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR06; RXJ 0535; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:29:50, Side 2: 00:23:11): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Continued from SR05; see the notes for details. Probably the original tape.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 282.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1963-08-16t23.aif - rcr1963-08-16t39.aif; 17 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tuning/"Live And Let Live" 00:02:10
      "Panhandle Country" 00:02:14
      "Little Maggie" [the beginning is cut off] 00:02:28
      "House Carpenter" ("what happens when you cross an abalone with a crocodile?") 00:03:34
      "If I Lose" ("pick a number between 1 and 10") 00:03:17
      "Remington Ride" 00:03:03
      "Good Woman's Love" 00:03:08
      "Mocking Banjo" 00:02:26
      "Sitting On Top Of The World" [the beginning is cut off] 00:01:57
      "'T' For Texas" [the first notes of the song may have been cut off; reel direction change] 00:05:12
      "Pain In My Heart" 00:02:28
      "All The Good Times" [with slow tempo false start] 00:04:24
      "Bells of St. Mary's" 00:03:30
      "Boston Burglar" 00:03:30
      "Someday You'll Call My Name" 00:03:46
      "Teardrops In My Eyes" 00:03:25
      "I'm On My Way To The Old Home" 00:01:56
    - Song list and production notes for SR05 and SR06, after January 5, 2011, 1963 August 16 (Reel 281&282).txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list, undated, 1963 August 16 Set 3 (Reel#282).pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at The Cabale, August 18, 1963, AFC 2011/011: SR07
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR07; RXJ 0536; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; 00:25:41): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Recorded at The Cabale, 2504 San Pablo, Berkeley, California. Personnel: Scott Hambly, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith, Sandy Rothman).
      According to the documentation this recording may be the last set of this performance. Recorded on one side of the tape only. Probably the original tape.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 283.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1963-08-18t01.aif - rcr1963-08-18t09.aif; 9 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tuning/"Walking Cane" 00:02:00
      "Childish Love" 00:02:56
      "Fireball Mail"/false start of the next song 00:03:05
      "Salty Dog" 00:02:40
      "I Cried Again" ("I've got a special invention") 00:04:14
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:03:22
      "Love Please Come Home" 00:02:22
      "I Ain't Broke But I'm Badly Bent" ("we're gonna call it the end of our reunion") 00:02:55
      "Panhandle Country" 00:02:16
    - Song list and production notes for SR07, January 4, 2011, rcr1963-08-18.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list, undated, rcr1963-08-18 _Reel 283_.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers at The Cabale, August 25, 1963, AFC 2011/011: SR08
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR08; RXJ 0537; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 1: 00:17:05, Side 2: 00:02:29): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Recorded at The Cabale, 2504 San Pablo, Berkeley, California. Personnel: Scott Hambly, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith, Sandy Rothman.
      Archivist's note: More songs should have been on the source tape, but were not captured or accidentally erased due to a dubbing problem.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1963-08-25t01.aif - rcr1963-08-25t08.aif; 8 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Little Birdie" [partial; fades in] 00:02:24
      "Prisoner's Song" 00:02:17
      "Long Black Veil" [the beginning of the song is cut off] 00:03:04
      Band history banter 00:01:02
      "Teardrops In My Eyes" 00:02:00
      "Auld Lang Syne" 00:02:53
      "Boston Burglar" 00:03:13
      "Tragic Romance" 00:02:24
    - Song list and production notes for SR08, December 16, 2010, rcr1963-08-25.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list, undated, rcr1963-08-25 _Reel 284_.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - The Crabgrassers at The Cabale, Berkeley, California, November 1963, AFC 2011/011: SR46
    - Sound recording (cut-level), cg1963-11-00t01.aif - cg1963-11-00t33.aif; 33 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Introduction by Dave Fredrickson 00:00:34
      "Flop Eared Mule" 00:01:23
      "Charles Guiteau" 00:03:02
      "Last Letter" 00:02:09
      "Waves On The Sea" 00:02:16
      "Cigarettes, Whiskey And Wild, Wild Women" 00:02:55
      "Little Willie" 00:02:00
      "Girl Of Constant Sorrow" 00:03:08
      "Dark As A Dungeon" 00:02:55
      "Dust On The Bible" 00:02:05
      "Love Please Come Home" 00:01:36
      "Don't Give Your Heart To A Rambler" 00:02:07
      "In The Summertime" 00:01:45
      "There Is A Trap" 00:01:52
      "Greenback Dollar" 00:03:29
      "Tramp On The Street" 00:03:36
      "Your Cheatin' Heart" 00:02:41
      "Kawlija" 00:02:32
      "Your Long Journey" 00:02:28
      "Run Mountain" 00:03:35
      "Little Sadie" 00:01:37
      "Ragtime Annie" 00:01:37
      "Detour" 00:02:04
      "Willie Moore" 00:02:56
      "Streamline Cannonball" 00:02:12
      "Long Black Veil" 00:02:23
      "Jambalaya" 00:01:58
      "Wild Side Of Life" 00:03:32
      "Live And Let Live" 00:02:17
      "Pick Me Up On Your Way Down" 00:02:10
      "Freight Train Blues" 00:02:40
      "You Turned Your Back" 00:02:10
      "Six More Miles" 00:02:09
    - Song list and production notes for SR46, February 18, 2013, cg1963-11-00.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Photograph of The Crabgrassers, undated, cg 1963-11-00.pdf; 1 photograph: black and white, scanned from a manuscript (.pdf)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers; The Country Boys, December 22, 1961, April 30, 1962, undated, AFC 2011/011: SR09
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR09; RXJ 0538; 1 sound tape reel (polyester; Side 00:31:50, Side 2: 00:31:09): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Archivist's note: Elapsed times are from AFC's transfer of the sound tape reel.
      Redwood Canyon Ramblers
      Recorded in Scott Hambly's basement, December 22, 1961.
      "Bluegrass Breakdown" [the beginning of the song is cut off] 00:01:51
      "Out In The Cold World (Wandering Boy)" 00:02:17
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:02:42
      "Home Sweet Home" 00:02:49
      "Foggy Mountain Breakdown" 00:02:31
      "Salty Dog" 00:02:13
      "Panhandle Country" 00:01:49
      "Under The Double Eagle" 00:04:02
      "Ruby" 00:02:03
      "Hard Times" 00:01:13
      "Long Journey Home" 00:02:08
      "Banjo Fling" 00:01:26
      "Teardrops In My Eyes" 00:02:02
      "Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms" [ends abruptly when the tape runs out] 00:02:15
      The Country Boys
      At The Ash Grove, Los Angeles, California, April 30, 1962.
      "Rocky Run" 00:02:06
      "Rawhide" 00:03:02
      Set intro/"Roll In My Sweet Baby's Arms" 00:02:07
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:01:57
      "Way Downtown" 00:02:44
      "Footprints In The Snow" 00:02:31
      "Old Rattler" 00:02:20
      The Monroe Brothers
      Bill Monroe and Charlie Monroe, recorded at Town Hall Party (TV broadcast), Compton, California, December 24, 1955.
      "Turkey In The Straw" 00:02:00
      "Footprints In The Snow" 00:02:53
      "Blue Moon Of Kentucky" 00:02:47
      "Cheyenne" 00:03:41
      "Christmas Time's A Comin'" [incomplete] 00:02:10
  - Out West Berkeley - various artists - Arhoolie Records sessions, 1963-1864, AFC 2011/011: SR47
    - Sound recording (cut-level), arhoolie01.aif - arhoolie08.aif; 8 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tracks 1-6 are from the LP (Arhoolie F4001). Tracks 7-8 are from the 45 rpm release (Arhoolie 505).
      "Lady Gay" - Janet Smith 00:03:14
      "The Unicorn" - Janet Smith 00:07:09
      "Buttermilk Hill" - Janet Smith 00:02:32
      "Long Black Veil" - Pete Berg and Toni Brown 00:02:42
      "Charles Guiteau" - The Crabgrassers 00:03:31
      "Don't Forget Me Love" - Toni Brown 00:02:03
      "How Could I Stand It" - Toni Brown 00:02:42
      "You Turned Your Back" - Toni Brown 00:02:19
    - Song list and production notes for SR47, undated, Arhoolie Records-Out West Berkeley.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Out West Berkeley - front and back covers, 1965, OWB cover-front.jpg, OWB cover-back.jpg; 2 photographs: color, digital (.jpg)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers; Opry dubs; Charlie Poole 78 dubs, 1927-1928, February 22, 1964, February 20, 1965, March 6, 1965, undated, AFC 2011/011: SR10
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR10; RXJ 0539; 1 sound tape reel (acetate; Side 1: 00:26:13, Side 2: 00:23:58): analog, 7 1/2 ips, half track, mono; 7 in.
      Redwood Canyon Ramblers, February 22, 1964. Demo tape recorded at 420 E. 6th Street, Bloomington, Indiana. Personnel: Mayne Smith, guitar; Scott Hambly, mandolin; Ann Rosenberg, bass; Neil Rosenberg, banjo.
      According to the documentation, this part of the tape is also on AFC 2002/009: SR280.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 106.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1964-02-22t01.aif - rcr1964-02-22t10.aif, opry1965-02-22t01.aif - opry1965-02-22t03.aif, opry1965-03-06t01.aif; 14 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Archivist's note: Elapsed times for the Charlie Poole dubs come from the AFC transfer of the tape recording.
      Side 1
      "House Carpenter" - vocal by Mayne Smith 00:02:52
      "Auld Lang Syne" 00:02:31
      "Childish Love" - vocal by Scott Hambly 00:02:33
      "Boston Burglar" - vocal by Mayne Smith 00:02:54
      "I Got Stripes" - vocal by Mayne Smith 00:02:34
      "Someday You'll Call My Name" - vocal by Mayne Smith; includes false start 00:02:49
      "Midnight Train" - vocal by Mayne Smith and Neil Rosenberg 00:03:16
      "Charles Guiteau" - written and sung by Mayne Smith; includes false start 00:02:39
      "I'll Walk Out On You" - vocal by Mayne Smith 00:02:03
      "I Ain't Broke But I'm Badly Bent" - lead by Mayne Smith, with Scott Hambly and Neil Rosenberg on trio 00:01:28
      Grand Ole Opry (February 20, 1965)
      Dubbed from a live performance broadcast on WSM radio.
      Intro/"Mary At The Home Place" - Bill Monroe & His Bluegrass Boys 00:02:42
      Kirk McGee Interview by Roy Acuff/Bill Cheatham (McGee Brothers) 00:01:14
      "Gotta Travel On" - Bill Monroe & His Bluegrass Boys 00:02:08
      Grand Ole Opry (March 6, 1965)
      Dubbed from the radio.
      "Father's Table Grace" - Flatt and Scruggs 00:02:42
      Charlie Poole and the North Carolina Ramblers
      Columbia recordings
      "Ramblin' Blues" (1928; Columbia 15286-D) 00:03:02
      "Coon From Tennessee" (1927; Columbia 15215-D) 00:03:04
      "Letter That Never Came" (1927; Columbia 15179-D) 00:02:25
      "Fallen By The Wayside" [beginning of the song is cut off](1927, Columbia 15179-D) 00:02:46
      "It's Moving Day" (undated; Columbia 15545-D) 00:03:19
    - Song list and production notes for SR10, December 14, 2010, Reel 106.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Typed list of all songs on the source tape, undated, rcr1964-02-22 Reel 106 Notes.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    - Images of a microphone and microphone stand, undated, IMG_2205.jpg, IMG_2208.jpg, IMG_2209_2.jpg, IMG_2210.jpg; 4 photographs: color, digital (.jpg)
  - Home recording, King Salmon, Alaska - Scott Hambly, March 13, 1965, AFC 2011/011: SR48
    - Sound recording (cut-level), sh1965-03-13t01.aif - sh1965-03-13t04.aif; 4 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Little Maggie" [fragment] 00:00:08
      "Footprints In The Snow" 00:02:41
      "Auld Lang Syne" 00:00:41
      Unidentified fragment 00:00:03
    - Song list and production notes for SR48, April 6, 2011, sh1965-03-13.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Indiana University Folksong Record Project, May 1965, AFC 2011/011: SR49
    - Sound recording (cut-level), phr1965-05-00t01.aif - phr1965-05-00t30.aif; 30 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Recorded at Don Sheets Recording Studio, Nashville, Tennessee. See AFC 2002/009: SR197 for similar versions of these recordings.
      Tom Forman
      "He Was A Friend Of Mine" 00:04:12
      "Venezuela" [take 1] 00:02:38
      "Venezuela" [take 2] 00:05:17
      "Mirror, Mirror On The Wall" 00:03:36
      "The Handsome Cabin Boy" 00:03:29
      Susie Rider
      "How Long Blues" 00:01:52
      Muddy Water Blues [with Pete Aceves on harmonica] 00:01:54
      "Little Maggie" 00:02:41
      Pigeon Hill Ramblers
      "Leavin' Tennessee" 00:02:43
      "Arthritis Blues" 00:02:28
      "Today Has Been A Lonesome Day" 00:03:24
      "Little Birdie" 00:02:48
      "Prisoner's Song" 00:02:19
      "Bury Me Beneath The Willow" 00:02:21
      Greg Hildebrand
      "Farm Song (Down On My Farm)" 00:02:17
      "No More Reds In The Union" 00:01:52
      "Cocaine" 00:03:14
      "Song Of My Hands" 00:03:21
      Hootchie Kootchie Jug Busters
      Instrumental 00:01:58
      "You're Some Ugly Child" 00:01:54
      "Rampart Street" [take 1; incomplete] 00:01:38
      "Rampart Street" [take 2] 00:02:14
      "Ace In The Hole" 00:03:07
      "2:19" 00:02:50
      "Brownsville" 00:02:27
      Pete Aceves and Eric Levin
      "Baby Please Don't Go" 00:01:55
      "Low Down and Dirty (That's Alright, Mama)" 00:02:19
      "Skingame" 00:01:54
      "Floating Bridge" 00:02:32
      Unidentified musician
      Harmonica 00:00:42
    - Song list and production notes for SR49, February 4, 2912, phr1965-05-00.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - List of songs and performers, undated, IUFC recording sessions.docx; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.doc)
    - IUFC (Indiana University Folksong Club) master recordings for projected record (handwritten original), undated, 1965 IU Folk Record Project-1.pdf; 2 manuscripts: black and white, digital (.pdf)
      List of songs, handwritten by Neil Rosenberg
    - IUFC (Indiana University Folksong Club) master recordings for projected record (typed from the handwritten original), undated, 1965 IU Folk Record Project-2.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
      Typed list of songs, from Neil Rosenberg's handwritten original
    - Order form and educational agreement form, April 19, 2012, MiksisIUArchivesOrder.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
      Details of the download and use agreement between Indiana University and Brian Miksis
  - Demo session, Berkeley, California - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, January 3, 1968, AFC 2011/011: SR50
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1968-01-03t01.aif - rcr1968-01-03t03.aif; 3 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "We'll Meet Again Sweetheart" 00:02:47
      "Teardrops In My Eyes" 00:02:28
      "My Little Georgia Rose" 00:02:19
    - Song list and production notes for SR50, April 6, 2011, rcr1968-01-03.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
  - Holiday reunion jam in the Hambly residence basement, Berkeley, California - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, December 27, 1980, AFC 2011/011: SR51
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1980-12-27t01.aif - rcr1980-12-27t15.aif; 15 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:02:29
      "Fireball Mail" 00:02:43
      "Paddy On The Turnpike" 00:02:37
      "Leaning On The Everlasting Arms" 00:02:16
      "Mocking Banjo" 00:01:58
      "Foggy Mountain Breakdown" 00:02:18
      "Darling Nelly Gray" 00:02:56
      "Here Today And Gone Tomorrow" 00:02:26
      "Teardrops In My Eyes" 00:02:22
      "Salty Dog" 00:02:18
      "We'll Meet Again Sweetheart" 00:02:36
      "Wheel Hoss" 00:03:00
      "Gray Eagle" [cassette side change] 00:01:03
      "House Carpenter" 00:04:39
      "They'll Know Who I Am" [Mayne Smith original] 00:02:31
    - Song list and production notes for SR51, April 6, 2011, rcr1980-12-27.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - J-card with handwritten song list, undated, rcr1980-12-27.jpg; 1 manuscript: color, digital (.jpg)
  - Redwood Canyon Ramblers reunion jam, June 6, 1987, AFC 2011/011: SR11
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR11; RYP 7388; 1 sound cassette (Side 1: 00:47:29, Side 2: 00:47:28): analog, 1 7/8 ips, Type II, stereo.
      Recorded at the Rosenberg residence, 784 Grizzly Peak Blvd., Berkeley, California. Personnel: Scott Hambly, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith, Sandy Rothman.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 285.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1987-06-06t01.aif - rcr1987-06-06t35.aif; 35 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tuning/"Wreck Of The Old 97" 00:04:04
      Discussing Mayne's guitar 00:01:53
      "Change It When It Breaks" [incomplete] 00:01:54
      Tuning/banter 00:01:19
      "Here Today" 00:02:46
      Tuning/banter 00:01:28
      "Wheel Hoss" 00:02:58
      Discussing "Wheel Hoss"/next song 00:02:45
      "Heaven Seemed So Near" 00:03:43
      "Jesse James" 00:02:58
      Discussion of 1988 reunion gig 00:01:04
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:03:13
      "UAW-CIO" 00:03:09
      Discussion/tuning of "Rock Me Baby" 00:02:20
      "Rock Me Baby" 00:04:14
      Discussion/tuning of "Live And Let Live" 00:01:53
      "Live And Let Live" 00:02:38
      Banter/tuning [tape change side] 00:03:11
      "Policeman" [fragment] 00:01:03
      "Backwater Blues" 00:04:49
      Banter/tuning of "Letters Have No Arms" 00:02:09
      "Letters Have No Arms" 00:02:58
      Banter 00:01:13
      "House Carpenter" 00:05:18
      Banter/tuning of "Childish Love" 00:02:51
      "Childish Love" 00:02:44
      Banter/tuning of "Old Joe Clark" 00:01:07
      "Old Joe Clark" 00:02:45
      "Don't Let The Stars Get In Your Eyes" 00:03:18
      Banter/tuning of "Long Black Veil" 00:01:00
      "Long Black Veil" 00:05:10
      "Little Maggie" 00:03:24
      Banter/tuning of "Red Rocking Chair" 00:02:44
      "Red Rocking Chair"/tuning for "Dark Hollow" 00:03:34
      "Dark Hollow" [the song ends abruptly when the tape runs out] 00:01:18
    - Song list and production notes for SR11, January 9, 2011, rcr1987-06-06.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list and production notes, undated, rcr1987-06-06 _Reel 285_.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Demo session - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, June 5, 1988, AFC 2011/011: SR12
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR12; RYP 7389; 1 sound cassette (00:20:30): analog, 1 7/8 ips, Type I, stereo.
      Recorded at Mayne Smith's residence, 6265 Highland Ave., Richmond, California. Personnel: Scott Hambly, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith, Sandy Rothman. Recording session produced by Sandy Rothman.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 286.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1988-06-05t01.aif - rcr1988-06-05t07.aif; 7 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "After Dark" 00:03:32
      Banter/"Dave Jones" 00:01:20
      "They'll Know Who I Am" [with false start] 00:02:54
      "Drifting Too Far From The Shore" 00:03:43
      "Farewell Blues" 00:01:40
      "House Carpenter" 00:04:38
      "Back In The Saddle Again" 00:02:21
    - Song list and production notes for SR12, January 10, 2011, 1988 June 5 (Reel 286).txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Handwritten song list on the cassette J-card, circa 1988, 1988 June 5 (Reel 286).pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
    - Members of the Redwood Canyon Ramblers, probably June 5, 1988, RCR-6-88-bySR.jpg; 1 photograph: color, digital (.jpg)
      Left to right: Scott Hambly, Mayne Smith, Neil V. Rosenberg
  - Demo session for the Japanese promoter - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, October 20, 1990, AFC 2011/011: SR13
    - Sound recording (full), AFC 2011/011: SR13; RYP 7390; 1 sound cassette (00:37:23): analog, 1 7/8 ips, Type II, stereo.
      Recorded at Scott Hambly's residence, 2226 Benvenue Ave., Berkeley, California. Personnel: Sandy Rothman, Neil Rosenberg, Mayne Smith). The demo was produced by Sandy Rothman.
      Original Rosenberg inventory number: tape 287.
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1990-10-20t01.aif - rcr1990-10-20t12.aif; 12 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      "House Carpenter" [first time] 00:05:14
      "House Carpenter" [second time] 00:05:13
      "Pike County Breakdown" 00:02:39
      "Little Willie" [first time] 00:02:56
      "Little Willie" [second time] 00:02:55
      "Weeping Willow" [first time] 00:02:44
      "Weeping Willow" [second time] 00:02:44
      "Heaven Seemed So Near" [first time] 00:02:34
      "Heaven Seemed So Near" [second time] 00:02:22
      "Willow Garden" [first time] 00:02:36
      "Willow Garden" [second time] 00:02:33
      "Willow Garden" [third time] 00:02:32
    - Song list and production notes for SR13, January 10, 2011, rcr1990-10-20.txt; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.txt)
    - Cassette j-card with handwritten song list, circa 1990, rcr1990-10-20 _Reel 287_.pdf; 1 manuscript: black and white, digital (.pdf)
  - Japan tour: train ride - Redwood Canyon Ramblers, April 30, 1991, April 31, 1990; AFC 2011/011: SR52
    - Sound recording (cut-level), rcr1991-04-30at01.aif - rcr1991-04-30at06.aif; 6 sound files: high-resolution files, digital (.aif)
      Tape 1
      Discussion of possible opening songs 00:03:27
      Mayne talks about pre-bluegrass core repertoire 00:04:54
      Toru [Mitsui] talks about his musical development 00:03:37